Alexander Musayev

Date of birth: 17 Jul 1981 E-mail/jabber: alex.musayev@gmail.com

Location: Saint-Petersburg, Russia Skype: dreikanter

Education: Higher technical Phone: +7 (905) 266-61-66

Skills and specialization

Eight years experience in software design and development. UI/UX design and prototyping. Requirements analysis, tasks decomposition and estimation. Creating specifications and project documentation. Keeping things in order and transforming the complex into the simple.

- Languages, frameworks, libraries: C# (.net 1.1-4.0, winforms/wpf, wcf, spring.net, moq, xunit, nunit, devexpress, wix, msmq, zeromq, log4net, nlog), python (django, web.py), php (wordpress plugin api, ado db, codeigniter).
- Databases: mysql, sqlite, microsoft sql server (express, ce), oracle.
- Web: html (4, 5), xhtml, css (2, 3), микроформаты. Servers: apache, nginx.
- Version control: svn, git.
- **IDE and tools:** microsoft visual studio 6.0-2010, jetbrains pycharm, microsoft visio, case studio, windows cli, linux shell, adobe photoshop, mindjet mindmanager.
- English and Russian languages.

Mission

Invent and develop high-quality and popular products bringing joy not only by the implemented functionality, but by the fact of their existence itself. Increase the amount of order and meaning in the world.

Interests

Product development, analysis, UI/UX design, information architecture, distributed systems, web technologies.

Experience

Senior software developer

Luxoft, Saint-Petersburg (http://luxoft.com) Jan 2012 — Present time

Software developer (Department of outsourcing)

Lanit-Tercom, Saint-Petersburg (http://lanit-tercom.ru)
Aug 2008 — Dec 2011

Responsibility:

- Enterprise software development (desktop applications and web services), testing, deployment and support (.NET/C#, PL/SQL, Java, Flex).
- Requirements analyzis, tasks decomposition and estimation, creating specifications and project docimentation.
- UI prototyping and development, UI logic formalization.

Achievements:

- Analytical information system for thermal power plants for Infoenergo Ltd. (Russia).
- Web-based media management system for DTS Medien AG (Germany).
- Medical data management system for Huntington Hospital (California, USA) / dbMotion Ltd. (Israel).

Freelance developer (Department of Research and Development)

Sevzapmontazhavtomatika LLC, Saint-Petersburg (http://szma.com) Aug 2006 — Dec 2009

Responsibility:

- Architecture design for distributed software.
- Requirements analysis, specification drafting and project documentation.
- Software development, testing, deployment and support (C#, Matlab, MQL, MySQL, PHP).
- Technical documentation and user manuals drafting.

Achievements:

- Web service for financial data collection, verification, and analysis.
- Middleware for Matlab integration with Metaquotes MetaTrader (trading platform).

Post graduate student

SPIIRAS, Saint-Petersburg (http://spiiras.nw.ru)
Dec 2004 — Dec 2008

Responsibility:

- Research in the field of mathematical modeling, scientific conferences participation.
- Participating in development of Computer-aided Modeling System for the Large-scale Social Economic Projects (Russian Foundation for Basic Research grant).
- Experimental software development (C#).
- Training cource development for third-year university students.

Achievements:

• A number of publications in science magazines and institute proceedings on mathematical modelling and enterprise automation.

Professor assistant

SPbUWC, Saint-Petersburg (http://spbuwc.ru) Oct 2006 — Jul 2008

Responsibility:

- Training cource development for university students.
- Lecturing and running workshops on C++ programming, seminars organization on enterprise software development.
- Exams admission, participating in the examination committee for the "Information Security" specialty.

Achievements:

- Practical programming experience in high-level languages for about 50 university students.
- Lecture notes on C++ programming.

Software developer

7+11 Company Ltd., Saint-Petersburg (http://7plus11.ru)
Jul 2003 — Oct 2007

Responsibility:

- Distributed systems design and developing for enterprise automation and monitoring systems.
- Data collection and visualization systems development.
- Embedded software testing, deployment and support.
- Requirements analysis, technical documentation.
- Office LAN administration (25 workplaces).

Achievements:

- Launched automated control systems for VTB Bank Headquarters, Kronverk Business Center and a number of other office and residential buildings in Saint-Petersburg.
- Kilowatt-hours and giga-calories saved by control algorithms optimization for embedded systems.

Personal non-commercial projects for the last 3 years

- Bibliography generator for science texts based on the GOST 7.0.5-2008 standard requirements (a tool which helps to get rid of a cumbersome list of weak rules which should be kept in mind during bibliography drafting).
- Open source blog CMS: Motoko Smart Blogging System (http://motoko.ru).
- Proven concept of Git version control system usage for web content management (specialized CMS for wishlists generation based on Git backend).
- Google Chrome browser extensions with a few thousands of users (http://b23.ru/33f7).
- A number of Wordpress plugins (e.g. http://paradigm.ru/wp-postlist).

Education

Higher: St. Petersburg State University of Airspace Instrumentation (SUAI)

Department of Automatic Control Systems

Specialty: Automatic Control and Information Processing Systems

1998 - 2004

Postgraduate: St. Petersburg Institute for Informatics and Automation of Russian

Academy of Sciences (SPIIRAS)

Specialty: Mathematical and Software Support of Computers,

Complex Systems and Networks

2004 - 2008

Miscellaneous

• Brainbench certifacates: C, HTML.

- Artyom Gorbunov's Educational Center certificate: User Experience design and Information Visualization.
- Careerlab certificate: High Level Architecture Design With UML.
- Community membership: ACM, WSG, UX Russia.
- Traveling passport is available. Inland and abroad business trips experience.